{
  "age": 55,
  "aliases": [
    "/state-house/district-45/sharon-mccollough/"
  ],
  "background": "Educator, Baltimore City Public School Professional Counselor, Private Consulting",
  "directory": "content/primary/state-house/district-45",
  "district": 45,
  "dob": "5/1/1963",
  "education": "BS, Computer Information Systems Notre Dame of Maryland University MS, Clinical Community Counseling Johns Hopkins University Post Masters, Leadership in Teaching/Library Media Notre Dame of Maryland University",
  "filename": "sharon-mccollough.md",
  "full-name": "Sharon McCollough",
  "general-only": false,
  "jurisdiction": "Baltimore City",
  "last-name": "McCollough",
  "party": "Democrat",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "Yes, I support the findings of The Kirwan Commission.  As an educator and a product of the Baltimore City Public School System, I commend the legislators for passing the preliminary package and I hope to join the team and be in support of the AFT-Maryland ongoing recommendations as proposed from the study.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "I will need to confer with transportation experts and legislators on the changes implemented before I determine what is adequate.  I am aware that a number of citizens are not too happy or supportive of the new BaltimoreLink, which is an ongoing discussion.  I commend the department of transportation for addressing the citizens frustrations and concerns by hosting a number of discussion forums.",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "I am not 100% at this time to confirm a solid, No.  However, I believe that recreational marijuana is a gateway drug; especially when treated or laced with other synthetic products.  I need to understand how recreational marijuana is regulated.  Are restrictions and if so what are they?",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "As a new delegate, I would prefer to confer with  Environmental experts before implementing any new steps.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "I believe all Americans deserve affordable quality health care and in efforts to ensure the broadest possible access, I prefer to  confer with seasoned colleagues and collaborate with experts to devise a best practice.",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "I would like the state to provide financially support for initiatives that yield results that are reforming and transforming individuals that have been released from prison to help them not return to a life of crime.  Create more job opportunities, 21st century training and increase living wages for working families.  Provide funding for programs for after school initiatives and other family holistic programs.",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "Fair with consideration for improvement.  Continue income tax incentive practices to attract new job creations.  To attract more industries to Baltimore City, we must help and support initiatives to combat our crime rate and our challenging justice system.",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "As a new delegate, I prefer not to confirm a definite answer without seeking more understanding after:  researching past best practices and policies that support fairness and equity, confer with more experienced and seasoned legislators for best practices that will best serve the people that will be impacted as a result of the findings from the census.",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "I believe that public servants and public service professions should perform with integrity and transparency.  In addition, I also believe in teamwork, accountability and no one should be above reproach.   LEOBR appears and alludes that special privileges are offered to officers that can be viewed as being abused when there is questionable practices;  no investigations and or no open to the public accountability results.  Possibly,  language that supports more transparency, accountability, protection for our law enforcers, measures that will restore trust.",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "Narcan should be continued as a preventive measure, however, it is not treatment.  We need to evaluate our treatment facilities and implement more wrap around services.  Additional facilities may need to be initiated to cut down the wait list of those seeking or have been identified as needing treatment. Develop a tracking system of frequent emergency room flyers in efforts to provide services as an early onset measure.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "As a new delegate, I will need to confer with experienced colleagues and economic experts.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "Yes, it is clearly state what is required and measures to implement when requirements are not met or be called into questioning.",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-house",
  "residence": "Baltimore",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Sharon McCollough"
}
